# JERRIN BRIGHT

(+91) 98401 78777 | Chennai, India LinkedIn | Portfolio | Github | Mail | Scholar | Ngo | Blogs

## PERSONAL PROFILE STATEMENT

I am a versatile and self-motivated engineer highly skilled in **Autonomous Systems** and **Robotic Real-time Perception,** focusing on aerial and ground systems. My **research focuses** includes Lidar and Visual SLAM, Visual Odometry, Motion planning, Optical Flow, Visual Reconstruction, Sensor fusion, Computer Vision and Control Systems. I aim to work on research-oriented organizations that utilize and help in honing my skills.

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, India Bachelors of Technology in Mechanical Engineering Chettinad Vidyashram, Chennai, India CBSE – Computer Science June 2018-Present Cumulative GPA: 8.25/10.0 June 2003-May 2018 10<sup>th</sup> CGPA 9.4/10.0, 12<sup>th</sup> 83.2%

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Globalink Research Intern @ McMaster University, Ontario, Canada

Starting July 2021

Designing and testing software for controlling a pneumatically-powered soft robot arm. It will acquire real-time data from several sensors, and implement a suitable controller (e.g., model predictive control). Thus, applying advanced control systems to a real-world problem. (Supervised by Prof. Gary Bone)

Summer Research Intern @ Arizona State University, Phoenix, USA Starting May 2021
Using laser scanning, photogrammetry to digitalize environments via visualizing data collected from sensors

fusing into a unified system. DL algorithms are used for automated analysis. The digital representations made will be processed to provide insights to builders, stewards. (Supervised by Prof. Thomas Czerniawski)

Autonomous System Developer (ASD) - Intern @ Aero2Astro, India Oct 2020-Present

Developing ROS based autonomous navigation firmware using Visual Inertial SLAM concepts for indoor environment. Implementation was based on Sensor Fusion techniques, Extended Kalman Filters and is aimed to eradicate the need for GPS thus making the system/ firmware more reliable.

Data Science Intern @ BrainMagic InfoTech Pvt, Chennai, India

*May – July 2020* 

Automobile fault detection using vison techniques resulting in an IOU of 95%. Dimensional analysis was done to locate defects and monitor it. Later, was deployed in AWS using Amazon Sagemaker and S3 Buckets.

Project Research Intern @ Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan City, Taiwan ☑ April – June 2020
Built a robust smart parking system using semantic segmentation with Conv. Conditional Random Fields and Atrous Convolution enhancing the visual capability of the system. Sensor Fusion of Camera and IMU using EKF to avoid failures or losses or sparse environmental conditions. (Supervised by Prof. Wei-Tyng Hong)

**Team Captain and Co-Founder** @ **Atom Robotics, VIT Chennai, India** 

Jan 2019-Present
An Intelligent Robotics and Satellite exploration team consisting of 50+ aspiring young minds. The team focuses on Intelligent ground vehicles targeting IGVC, USA; Planetary Aerial System using VTOLS targeting IPAS, Mars society South Asia (MSSA); Satellites targeting Can-Sat, USA.

#### RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

Jerrin Bright et al 2021 IOP Conf. Ser.: Mater. Sci. Eng. 1012 012019

[ Paper link ]

Optimization of quadcopter frame using generative design and comparison with DJI F450 drone frame **Jerrin Bright et al (Currently in Progress)** 

Attention Embedded Squeeze-Excitation Residual Network- A CNN Benchmark for Medical Imaging

#### **AREA OF EXPERTISE**

Design and Simulation Tools Programming Tools Machine Learning Tools Platforms Linguistic knowledge Fusion360, SolidWorks, Proteus, Gazebo, RViz, MATLAB, SOFA C, C++, Python, Embedded System, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP OpenCV, TensorFlow, Matplotlib, NumPy, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit Windows, Linux Ubuntu, ROS, Raspbian OS Fluent: English; Intermediate: German, Hindi; Native: Tamil

## **ACCOLADES AND RECOGNITION**

Outstanding Research Paper Award 🗹

Recognized Galactic Problem Solver

Winner of KURUKSHETRA'20, CEG Anna University 2

Winner of CURRENTS'20, NIT Trichy

First Runner-up- Chennai International Youth Fest 🗷

RIACT 2020 International Conference NASA International Space Challenge RoboZest, National Level Techfest Line Follower (LiFo), ECE Department LiFo, Youth Development Consortium

## RESEARCH PROJECT

## 3D Pose Estimation using Stereo Visual Odometry 2

Jan – April 2020

Development of python package to reconstruct indoor and outdoor environments with diverse texture contrasts using Oriented FAST and Rotated Brief (ORB) feature detector and descriptor, FLANN for matching and RANSAC for outlier removal and Optical flow and PnP (DLT and Levenberg) for estimating the pose of robot.

# Autonomous MAV enhanced with door-to-door delivery topographies 2

Jan - April 2020

Developed a ROSpy based control system for a MAV to transverse to a set of GPSs setpoint autonomously picking and delivering a package. The Control System has two modules namely the Altitude (AC) and the position (PC) controller. AC stabilizes the drone using a PID based controller. PC takes in the target GPS coordinate has setpoint values and navigates successfully to the desired coordinates.

## SLAM embedded AGV for autonomous navigation Z

Sep - Oct 2020

Implemented 3D mapping using Kinect and IMU sensors in an indoor environment. Visual Inertial Navigation System was used to make the 3D map simulated in Gazebo environment and visualized 2D in RViz. Feature extraction via Oriented fast and Rotated Brief (ORB) was used for extraction and tracking.

## Intelligent Visual Robotic Inspection system for fault detection

Jan - Feb 2021

Automated visual inspection with CMOS Camera using local binary pattern histogram (LBPH) algorithm and dimensional analysis and detection of defects, faults and corrosions using Machine Learning approaches.

#### **Vestium- Smart Robotic Closet**

*May – Oct 2020* 

Designed an 80\*80 smart robotic furniture, which maximizes small spaces which will be poised to transform urban living. It is packed with plenty of space, hiding the bed when not in use, and allows to optimize space, at touch of a button. It can be used as an entertainment center, home office, bedroom, storage all in one closet.

#### **Robust Chest Xray Detection Architecture**

*July – Oct 2019* 

Built a convolutional system for x-ray detection of 14 different chest diseases. Some of the important tools used in the system are transfer learning fusing Residual Networks with UNet, Data Augmentation techniques and autonomous cropping using contours and extrema.

#### **Competition-based Robots**

Jan 2019 - Mar 2021

Designed and built Intelligent Ground Vehicles, Planetary Aerial Systems, Can-Satellites, Law Following Robot, Obstacle Racer, Robo-Soccer, Maze Runner, Sumo Robot, BattleBots with my team (Atom Robotics)

## **EXTRA-CURRICULAR**

#### **Machine Learning Contributor**

Oct 2020 – Feb 2021

Contributing ML blogs via CodeSpeedy to various blog-based companies. Have published 13 blogs.

#### Madras Scientific Research Foundation, NGO

Oct 2020 – Dec 2020

Researched on various cutting-edge areas of Manufacturing, Robotics and Vision systems. Also, spreading awareness on basic robotics in schools and amongst unprivileged kids was done as part of the NGO.

#### **Robotics Club, VIT**

Jan 2019 – Mar 2021

Have organized and led several events including the National Level Robotics Competition 'ROBOPRIX' as the Overall Student Coordinator, ABB Robotics and several other workshops.

#### **Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineer**

April 2019 – May 2020

Active Member of Robotics and Automation Society (RAS).

## **National Service Scheme**

May 2019 - Present

Active Member of Indian Government sponsored public service program. Part of several awareness programs – International Coastal Cleanup day, Community Services, planting of saplings, medical camps, etc.

#### **DECLARATION**

- I, Jerrin Bright, hereby affirm that the aforementioned statistics is true to my knowledge, as of Mar 9<sup>th</sup>, 2021.
- References available on request.